

P-107/A, Unique Park, Behala, Kolkata - 700034, West Bengal, India

🛘 +91-9836205250 | 🔀 rajdeep1989.iitkgp@gmail.com | 🌴 rajdeep345.github.io | 🞏 Rajdeep Mukherjee | 🖸 rajdeep345 | 🛅 rajdeepMukherjee89/

Summary_

I am a fifth-year PhD Student at the Dept. of CSE, IIT Kharagpur advised by Prof. Pawan Goyal and Prof. Sourangshu Bhattacharya. As part of the Complex Networks Research Group (CNeRG), I work on problems that lie at the intersection of Natural Language Processing, Information Retrieval, and Computational Social Science. I did my Masters from IIIT Delhi and Bachelors from Jadavpur University. Additionally, I have four years of professional experience with PwC India specializing in Data Warehousing, Data Modeling and Business Intelligence using Microsoft Technologies.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Kharagpur

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

- · Domain of Research Natural Language Processing, Information Retrieval, Computational Social Science
- Supervisors: Prof. Pawan Goyal, Prof. Sourangshu Bhattacharya

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology (IIIT) Delhi

M.TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

• CGPA: 9.11, Ranked 1st in Information Security Specialization (with thesis)

• Supervisor: M.Tech Thesis

B.E. IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Jadavpur University, Kolkata

• CGPA: 8.59, University Gold Medalist, TCS Best Student Project awardee.

• Supervisor: Prof. Samiran Chattopadhyay | Bachelors Thesis

Kendriya Vidyalaya (ONGC) Chandkheda, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

ALL INDIA SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION (AISSCE)

· Percentage: 91.8 %

Kendriya Vidyalaya (ONGC) Chandkheda, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

ALL INDIA SECONDARY SCHOOL EXAMINATION (AISSE)

· Percentage: 94.2 % · Adjudged School Topper.

SENIOR PROJECT OFFICER

Work Experience

IBM Research Labs RESEARCH INTERN

· Worked with Dipyaman Banerjee and Kuntal Dey towards the development of an efficient deep learning-based solution for identifying and recognizing sounds that do not contain a speech component.

- Participated in the Bird Audio Detection task as a part of IEEE AASP DCASE2018 Challenge.
- Our team secured 7th rank worldwide (1st in India) among all the participants. Challenge Results
- Our work was accepted as a **Poster** at DCASE2018 Workshop, held in Surrey, UK (November 2018).

Indian Institute of Technology Kharagpur

• Worked on Online Social Network Analysis as part of CNeRG.

Explored areas like Opinion Dynamics, Rumor Detection, and Click-bait Detection.

PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC) India

Kolkata, India

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT Aug 2011 - Jul 2015

- Worked as a Business Intelligence (BI) developer and Data Modeler in the Advisory Line of Service (LOS).
- Led projects in data warehousing, data modeling and BI using Microsoft technologies like MSBI suite, Visual Studio, MS SQL Server 2012 etc.
- Held several positions of responsibility and was instrumental in managing client expectations and relationships.

IBM IRL, Bangalore Kolkata, India

INTERN, IBM REMOTE MENTORING PROGRAM

Sep - Dec 2010

· Worked as an intern under the supervision of Dr. Chiranjib Sur, (the then) Research Scientist, High Performance Computing Group

OCTOBER 25, 2022 RAJDEEP MUKHERJEE · RÉSUMÉ

Kharagpur, India

Jan 2018 - Present

Delhi, India

Jul 2015 - Jul 2017

Kolkata, India

Jul 2007 - Jun 2011

Ahmedabad, India

2007

Ahmedabad, India

2005

Delhi, India

May - Jul 2018

Aug - Dec 2017



ECTSum: A New Benchmark Dataset For Bullet Point Summarization of Long Earnings Call Transcripts

Rajdeep Mukherjee, Abhinav Bohra, Akash Banerjee, Soumya Sharma, Manjunath Hegde, Afreen Shaikh, Shivani Shrivastava, Koustuv Dasgupta, Niloy Ganguly, Saptarshi Ghosh, Pawan Goyal

Paper | Dataset & Code

EMNLP 2022

MTLTS: A Multi-Task Framework To Obtain Trustworthy Summaries From Crisis-Related Microblogs

Rajdeep Mukherjee, Uppada Vishnu*, Hari Chandana Peruri*, Sourangshu Bhattacharya, Koustav Rudra, Pawan Goyal, Niloy Ganguly Paper | Code | Poster | Slides | Video | Citation

WSDM 2022

PASTE: A Tagging-Free Decoding Framework Using Pointer Networks for Aspect Sentiment Triplet Extraction

Rajdeep Mukherjee, Tapas Nayak, Yash Butala, Sourangshu Bhattacharya, Pawan Goyal

Paper | Code | Poster | Slides | Video | Citation

EMNLP 2021

Understanding the Role of Affect Dimensions in Detecting Emotions from Tweets: A Multi-task Approach

Rajdeep Mukherjee, Atharva Naik*, Sriyash Poddar*, Soham Dasgupta, Niloy Ganguly

Paper | Code | Blog | Poster | Slides | Video | Citation

SIGIR 2021

Reproducibility, Replicability and Beyond: Assessing Production Readiness of Aspect Based Sentiment Analysis in the Wild

Rajdeep Mukherjee*, Shreyas Shetty*, Subrata Chattopadhyay, Subhadeep Maji, Samik Datta, Pawan Goyal

Paper | Code | Slides | Video | Citation

ECIR 2021

Read what you need: Controllable Aspect-based Opinion Summarization of Tourist Reviews

Rajdeep Mukherjee, Hari Chandana Peruri, Uppada Vishnu, Pawan Goyal, Sourangshu Bhattacharya, Niloy Ganguly

Paper | Code | Slides | Video | Citation

SIGIR 2020

Addressing Forwarder's Dilemma: A Game-Theoretic Approach to Induce Cooperation in a Multi-hop Wireless Network

Saswati Mukherjee, Sreya Dey, **Rajdeep Mukherjee**, Matangini Chattopadhyay, Samiran Chattopadhyay, Debarshi Kumar Sanyal Paper | Citation

THIRD INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ADVANCES IN COMMUNICATION, NETWORK, AND COMPUTING, CNC 2012

Professional Activities

Program Committee Member

AAAI'23, EMNLP'22, SIGIR'22

Reviewer/Sub-Reviewer for Conference

AAAI'23, EMNLP'22, SIGIR'22, NAACL'22, ACL'22, NEURIPS'21, SIGIR'21, SDM'21, CODS-COMAD'21, EMNLP'20, SIGIR'20, LREC'20, EMNLP'19, CODS-COMAD'19

Reviewer/Sub-Reviewer for Journal

COMPUTER SPEECH AND LANGUAGE'22, IJDRR'21, TWEB'20, TCSS'20

Teaching Assistance _____

Spring '22	CS60075: Natural Language Processing, Instructor: Prof. Pawan Goyal	IIT Kharagpur
Autumn '21	CS60092: Information Retrieval, Instructor: Prof. Saptarshi Ghosh	IIT Kharagpur
Autumn '21	noc21-cs102: Natural Language Processing, Instructor: Prof. Pawan Goyal	NPTEL
Spring '21	CS60075: Natural Language Processing, Instructor: Prof. Pawan Goyal	IIT Kharagpur
Autumn '20	CS60083: Parameterized Algorithms, Instructors: Prof. Palash Dey, Prof. Sudeshna Kolay	IIT Kharagpur
Spring '20	CS60092: Information Retrieval, Instructors: Prof. Pawan Goyal, Prof. Saptarshi Ghosh	IIT Kharagpur
Autumn '19	CS29003: Algorithms-1 Lab, Instructors: Prof. Pawan Goyal, Prof. Animesh Mukherjee	IIT Kharagpur
Autumn '19	noc19-cs56: Natural Language Processing, Instructor: Prof. Pawan Goyal	NPTEL
Spring '19	Programming and Data Structures Lab, Instructor: Prof. Rogers Mathew	IIT Kharagpur
Autumn '18	Programming and Data Structures Lab , Instructors: Prof. Rogers Mathew, Prof. Sudebkumar Prasant Pal	IIT Kharagpur
Spring '17	CSE352/CSE552: Security Engineering, Instructor: Prof. Sambuddho Chakravarty	IIIT Delhi

Scholarships & Travel Grants _____

2022	Microsoft Research Travel Grant, awarded for attending WSDM 2022.	Microsoft Research
2022	ACM-India and IARCS Travel Grant, awarded for attending WSDM 2022.	ACM-India IARCS
2022	SIGIR Student Travel Grant, awarded for registering the paper.	WSDM 2022
2021	SIGIR Student Travel Grant , awarded for registering the paper and attending the conference (virtually).	SIGIR 2021
2020	SIGIR Student Travel Grant , awarded for registering the paper and attending the conference (virtually).	SIGIR 2020

Honors & Awards

2013	PwC Experience Award , awarded twice for demonstrating PwC Core values and behaviors.	Kolkata, India
2012	PwC Above and Beyond Award, awarded by Sudipto Ghosh, Partner, PwC.	Kolkata, India
2011	TCS Best Student Project Award and University Gold Medal , jointly awarded by Tata Consultancy Services and Jadavpur University.	Kolkata, India
2010	2nd place, IBM Technical Quiz, INSTRUO 2010 held at IIEST, Shibpur in the Technology Area on Green IT.	Kolkata, India
2005	2nd place, AISSE, KVS Ahmedabad Region , selected for CSIR Program on Youth for Leadership in Science.	Ahmedabad, India

Extracurricular Activities _____

2021	Judge, Open IIT: Eastern Vocal Competition	Kharagpur, India
2018	Permanent Membership, Eastern Technology Music Society (ETMS), IIT Kharagpur.	Kharagpur, India
2015	Permanent Membership, AudioBytes, Music Club, IIIT Delhi.	Delhi, India
2013	Silvers Plate Runners Up, Merchants' Cup Badminton Tournament.	Kolkata, India
2011	Multiple awards, National / State level Singing Competitions.	Kolkata, India
2010	Member, Organizing Committee, SRIJAN 2010, Annual Technical Fest, Jadavpur University.	Kolkata, India

References_____

Dr. Niloy Ganguly

Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kharagpur NILOY@CSE.IITKGP.AC.IN

Dr. Pawan Goyal

Associate Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kharagpur PAWANG@CSE.IITKGP.AC.IN

Dr. Sourangshu Bhattacharya

Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, IIT Kharagpur sourangshu@cse.iitkgp.ac.in